Hello friends welcome back to another new
video so friends in today's video
I am going to tell you about a very
good insurance company which is a
leading company in its segment and
it should
definitely be included in your portfolio because insurance
sector is such a sector
so stocks of this sector should definitely be included in your portfolio
so friends
before starting the video I
want to tell you all that if you have
not subscribed to the channel then you must subscribe to the channel
because I keep on bringing
videos related to good stocks related to stock market on
this channel and will keep on bringing in future also
so please subscribe to the channel
and hit the bell icon to
get the notification of the
company so general insurance company which does
not provide life insurance coverage and
except life insurance it
provides insurance
for vehicles commercial and
private vehicles and passenger vehicles so it
provides insurance for all these vehicles
and along with that it is also providing health insurance now
companies and
industries
also do their own insurance and
provide home insurance
if I talk about this sector then there is a lot of
scope in the sector
in India because a lot  This is an underprivileged sector
and is going to grow quite well.
Here ICICI Lombard General
Insurance is one of the leading and
established private sector general
insurance companies in India. It is a leading
company and it provides a well-diversified range
of products and risk
management solutions through multiple
distribution channels. So friends, if we
talk about its market capitalization, it has a
market capitalization of Rs 57,000 and Rs 66 crore. The
current price is Rs
1,164.
If we talk about it,
its high was Rs 1,548 and it reached Rs
1,071. So, we are seeing it trading around its low price.
If we
talk about the stock price, it is currently
showing Rs 36.4. The book value is Rs
20300.78%, return on capital employed is Rs
19.2%, return on equity is Rs 15.1%.
So,
going forward, if this company
splits its equity, then it is Rs 36.4.  If it does, there are chances of your shares getting multiples. So if
we take a look at the
chart here, you can see that
it has been continuously
moving in price since October and
during October
it was
trading at a level above 151600,
so right now it is available at a very discounted price, which
means you are getting it at a very
good price in the current market scenario.
So friends,
I want to tell you one more important thing here, if
you see the
3-year median P of this company, then it is
seen to be 47.8 and if we talk about the 5-year medium
P, then it is
46.8 and the 10-year medium P
is 47.8, which means we are getting it at a huge discount at the current
price. So if you like any
stock, then you can definitely add it to your portfolio.
This is not a recommendation,
but after doing research you can definitely add it.
So here you will do the
comparison, so in the price, however, there are
other companies also
like life insurance, SBI Life
Insurance, HDFC Life.  Insurance:
All these companies provide life insurance,
but ICICI Lombard
provides insurance without life insurance and there is a newly
established company, Star Health Insurance, which
provides insurance in a separate segment in the market. We will
make a video on this later. It provides only health insurance. So,
if we look at this sector, there is quite good
growth as well. If we take a look at the profit loss statement, there used to be
sales in 2011 and currently it has
generated sales of Rs 1626 crore, which means
we are seeing a continuous increase in our sales.
If we talk about
operating profit margin, which used to be negative in 2011
and till 2015 it used to be
negative and right now the
operating profit margin was six percent, so the
operating profit margin, friends,
shows us how much profit the company generates after running its operations.
Including tax, the
tax has been input in this.
Here we take a look at the net
profit, which used to be
negative in 2011 and
after 2013 the net profit came in positive
and it is increasing currently, we are
seeing a net profit of 1271 crores
and if we talk about apps, then apps also used to be
in negative for two-three years,
after that it is currently increasing and
showing us 25.89 kps and a very
important
parameter we will see right now is the compound debt
sales growth which is 16% for 10 years and the
compound profit growth is 17%, it is
16% for the last 5 years and the compound profit
growth is 13%, so here
you can see the return on equity which
we are seeing 19% for the last 10 years,
meaning return equity is that amount which is
how much percent return it is generating on the money of Sarhuldos, the
company is
generating a return of 19%, so  It is a very
good company and is a leading company
in its sector and if we talk about motor
vehicle
insurance, then
it has been in the leading position in motor vehicle insurance for
many years
and
here the
operating cash flow, cash flow here
in March 2022, we are seeing a net slowdown of 65,
which is in positive, which is
good, so if we talk about net slowdown here, then
this net slowdown can be
in positive or negative, if
you
calculate the net slowdown of 10 years, then most of the
net slowdown values ​​in it are in negative,
so it is a negative sign and
most of the values ​​are in positive, so it is a good
sign, so here we
see the maximum value of net slowdown in the post, then
it is a positive sign, so it is with the promoter,
which was
55.86%
holdings in December 2019, that is decreasing,
currently
holding 48.02%, all the eyewitnesses had
24% holdings, which had increased in between,
increase  It had become
28.12% and currently we are
seeing holdings of 24.7 24.07% and in the same
way,
so friends, here you can see that there is a
significant underpriced premium as a
percentage of GDP, so here you can see that there
is a lot of scope in India,
if we
look at it worldwide, then also this company has a lot of scope in this non-life
insurance market segment,
so
this company
seems to have the potential to grow a lot, so as an
investor I feel that this company
is a very good company to invest in,
so friends, if you liked this video then
like the video, subscribe to the channel
and press the bell icon
so that whenever we make similar stock market
videos, parallel notifications
reach you, see you all friends
on the next video, till then
Jai Bharat